In today's time, everyone takes a health insurance policy by
comparing the premiums and
benefits, but when the
time of claim comes, then it is understood that the policy
conditions were very good but the claim is not being
received, then the on-ground reality becomes clear to
us that many such new products have come
in the market, which we
will compare in this video, whose premiums are very
low and benefits are very high, but what are
its actual terms and conditions and
whether you should actually take this policy,
we will see this, in this video today
we will compare ICICI Elevate policy as well as
compare it with Neeva BPA
Aspire policy.  The
premiums of both these policies are quite low.
The benefits are also very good.  But
what is the reality on the actual grounds?   Let's
decipher it in this video.  So
before moving ahead, like this video of mine
, subscribe to my channel
so that I can bring important videos to
you like this.  Let us
compare both the policies.  First Point Room
Rent Limit.  There is no capping on room rent in both the policies.
But
in ICICI LBA Elevate, you will have to take a rider by doing
room modification, only then you
can take any room.  Otherwise by default ICICI
Lombard Elevate policy has a room cap of
Single Private Room.  But if you
take this rider room modifier then any of your
rooms is eligible.  So this rider I
call a must go if you are taking the policy.
Benefit number to no copayment.  There is
no copayment in both the policies.
Meaning the company will pay the entire 100% claim.
You don't need to pay even ₹1 from your pocket.
Benefit number three unlimited
restoration.
Unlimited restoration is available in both the policies with same
person same illness cover as well as same person
different illness.  Meaning, if I am getting admitted
and I am taking a claim, then again
after a month or after 10 days, if I am getting
admitted again for the same disease, then all of them will be
covered.  Benefit
number four no sublimits.  What does sublimits mean
?  Sublimits means
like a cap is placed on small diseases.  You will
get ₹00 for this disease.  You will
get ₹00 for this disease.  There is no such gap in this policy.
You will
get unlimited claims for every small and big illness.  The entire sum
insured will be available.  There are no submissions in both these policies.  The
name of the fifth benefit is day care procedure.
Day care procedures are covered in both the policies.  Now
what is day care procedure?  Day care procedure
refers to any illness that
in the past required four days of hospitalization.
Then the surgery would be done and
then you would get this claim.  But
what is the date today?
Due to modern technology, you will be admitted in 2 hours, undergo
surgery in 2 hours and come home.
Those are all day care procedures.
All those day care procedures
are covered in both the policies.  Benefit number
six is ​​pre and post hospitalization.
Pre and post hospitalization plays a very
major role.  Any one for long
term disease.  What does pre and post
mean?  There is
some doctor consultation before admission.  There are some doctor
reports and tests.
We visit the hospital.
All of them are in pre-hospitalization.
So all those things are covered in both the policies.
And post hospitalization means that
after discharge the doctor says
come after 10 days, come after 15 days.  Whether you have to
take medicine or do physiotherapy,
all these come under post hospitalization.
So both the policies have pre and
post cover.  ICICI LBAT
is ahead of Nivapa Aspire in pre and post benefits.
How ICICI's pre-hospitalization deadline
is 90 days and post-hospitalization deadline is 180 days.  Here if
we compare with Aspire then Aspire has
60 days and 180 days.  Benefit number
seven is consumable cover.
This is an optional rider in both the policies which is a must go.
You will have to take it in both the policies.
What is consumable cover?  This is
all the non-consumable items like
gloves, syringes, cotton, masks,
administration charges, nursing charges,
all these things are covered.  So as soon as
you take this cover, the entire 100%
claim will be made by the company.  You do
n't need to pay even ₹1 from your pocket.  The
name of this rider in ICICI LBD is Claim Protector.
Secondly, if we talk about Awair, the
name of this rider is Safeguard Plus.
Both these riders are compulsory
in both the policies.  So if you are thinking of buying it then you
must go for both these riders.
Benefit Number at No Claim Bonus.  Now
ICICI LBD Elevate
policy is far greater in No Claim Bonus than Niv UP Aspire.
How they see it.  In Niv UP Aspire,
your No Claim Bonus will increase by 100% every year,
maximum up to 10 times.  Meaning, if
you are taking a policy of Rs 25 lakh, then in 10 years
it will be Rs 2.5 crore.  It will not
grow after that.  Even if you claim and don't, it will
not increase.  If we talk about ICICI LB Elevate, it
will increase 100% every year here also
but there is no upper cap.  A policy of Rs 25 lakh will become Rs 2.5 crore in 10 years.
This will be Rs 5 crore in 20 years.
So here this is the plus point of
ICICI LBD Elevate as well as
in NIVPA Aspire, if you make a claim then your
sum insured will also reduce, your no claim
bonus will be included, here no
sum insured will ever reduce, but for this,
if you want this benefit in ICIC Almard Elevate, then you will have to
pay separately for it,
that is Power Booster Rider, this is also a must go must go
rider in your policy,
this rider is inbuilt in NIVPA Aspire,
benefit number nine pre
existing day is covered, there
is a jump start ride rider in ICIC LB Elevate,
due to which if you take the rider then asthma,
blood pressure, cholesterol, diabetes will be
covered from day one.  Where as Nivapa will
cover only two things that are
diabetes and blood pressure.  So its name is
Disease Management Rider.  So if someone has a
pre-existing disease and is
thinking of taking this policy, then both these riders can also be
added.  Now
we have compared all these benefits.  Now let us see
what is the unique point in both the policies?
What is the USP in both the policies?  Talking about ICICI LBD
Elevate, its unlimited
no claim bonus plays a major role
in making this policy a very comprehensive policy.  Secondly, the
best benefit in this is that
you can make unlimited claims once in your lifetime
after taking Infinite Care Rider.
Let's take an example, how will this rider work
?  This rider becomes active only after 2 years.
Now you understand that you are
taking a policy of Rs 25 lakh.  In 5 years the value of your policy will be Rs
1.25 crore.  Ok?  Now,
in the fifth year, if your single claim is
even for Rs 5 crore, then because of this infinite
care, the entire five codes will be settled.  So
isn't this a great benefit?
Due to this benefit, this policy
is called a very good policy.  Now let us see
what is the USP in Neevapa Aspire due to which
I tell people that you
can also look at this USP policy.  This policy is a
very good policy for young aspiring parents.  Only
maternity after 9 months
is covered in this.  If you take a policy for three years
together, then the maximum maternity
you will get will be Rs 75,000 on a policy of Rs 50 lakh and Rs 1
crore.  So you
can consider this also.  The second unique
benefit in this is its lock the clock.  This means
your premium will remain the same until you
make a claim.  So this is also good for young people
because their chances of getting a claim are very few,
so you can also consider IVP Aspire.
So now let's talk about the
conclusion, both the policies are
best in their own place.  We will see which policy will be best for you.
Talking about ICICI LB Elevate, it will
give you a very good cover in the long run along with unlimited no claim bonus in one policy.
Secondly, the one-time unlimited claim also
makes it very unique.  So this is
good for those who are
looking at keeping the policy in the long perspective.  Now let's talk about
ivp aspire.  So Neevapa
Aspire is the best policy in the market for the age group of 18 to 35.
First point.
Secondly, there is also maternity cover here, so it will be
a very good policy for young aspiring parents.
Because here the
newborn baby will be covered from day one.
So this also tells us a very interesting
fact.  So you
can consider both the policies.  So
if you have any
queries regarding both these policies then tell me by commenting below.
I will definitely answer for this.